const latest = {
  name: "Mr. Nisarg Bhavsar",
  about:
    "Students’ Branding and Relations Cell, IIT Kharagpur is excited to kick off the fresh edition of Spotlight with a new entry featuring Mr. Nisarg Bhavsar, a fourth-year dual degree student from the Department of Chemical Engineering.",
  department: "Department of Chemical Engineering",
  hall: "Vidyasagar Hall of Residence",
  work: "Research Assistant, Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT)",
  video: (
    <iframe
      width="560"
      height="315"
      src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/jb2gL4-zUD0?si=KGJGUd1Xw1t9eOnU&autoplay=1&mute=1"
      title="YouTube video player"
      frameborder="0"
      allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen"
      referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin"
      allowfullscreen
    ></iframe>
  ),
  medium:
    "https://medium.com/@sbrciitkgp/spotlight-mr-nisarg-bhavsar-cd49e2cbfd8e",
  linkedin: "https://www.linkedin.com/in/nisarg-bhavsar/",
  facebook: "https://www.facebook.com/nisarg.bhavsar.9678",
  instagram: "",
  mediumArticle: {
    introduction:
      "Students’ Branding and Relations Cell, IIT Kharagpur is excited to kick off the fresh edition of Spotlight with a new entry featuring Mr. Nisarg Bhavsar, a fourth-year dual degree student from the Department of Chemical Engineering. For more information, read the following interview:",
    interviewedBy: (
      <>
        <i>
          {" "}
          <b>Interviewed by — </b>Saksham Sinha, Student Member at Students’
          Branding and Relations Cell, IIT Kharagpur.
        </i>
      </>
    ),
    questions: [
      {
        question: "It would be great if you introduce yourself.",
        answer:
          "My name is Nisarg Bhavsar. I am a fourth-year undergraduate student at IIT Kharagpur, enrolled in a dual-degree course, and a boarder of Vidyasagar Hall of Residence. I am from the Chemical Engineering department, and when I am not doing anything serious, I like to write poetry and sometimes post on Twitter and LinkedIn.",
      },
      {
        question:
          "How has your life at IIT Kharagpur been for the past three and a half to four years?",
        answer:
          "When you put it that way 3.5 to 4 years I do feel old. But my journey has been transformative and evolving. I started with an online first year, and I used to be quite introverted. However, my time at KGP gave me opportunities to connect with my batchmates, seniors, and alumni, which helped me grow as a person, not just in the tech field.",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Your primary focus is in the field of machine learning, data science, and artificial intelligence. You are also a Machine Learning Engineer at Top Pulse. When did you realize that this was the path you wanted to pursue?",
        answer:
          "My journey was quite different from the conventional path. During my JEE preparation in high school (Class 11–12), my favorite subject was Biology, especially topics like evolution. I came across YouTube videos on evolutionary simulations, which fascinated me. How could someone simulate evolution using mathematics? That led me to discover genetic algorithms, which sparked my interest in machine learning and data science. Slowly, I learned about linear regression, computational biology, and AI, and my passion grew from there.",
      },
      {
        question:
          "You have completed multiple internships, including research-based ones at MIT and Swiggy. Could you share some insights about these experiences?",
        answer:
          "Initially, I worked on self-projects but felt stagnant, so I started approaching professors for research opportunities. I secured an internship at IIT Bombay in computer vision and another at IIM Ahmedabad. Later, I explored industry internships, working at startups and bigger companies like DevRev and Swiggy etc. Eventually, I realized I preferred research projects, so I applied to universities abroad, landing internships at Northeastern University and MIT. These experiences helped me grow not just technically but also in teamwork and communication.",
      },
      {
        question:
          "You have published several research papers and conference journals. Your work Satya received international recognition, and RTaC was presented at NSLP 2024 in Greece. Can you tell us more about these projects?",
        answer:
          "RTaC(Reimagining Tooling as Coding),a groundbreaking framework that transforms tool usage into a coding paradigm which started during Inter IIT Tech Meet, where we worked on tooling LLMs(Large Language Models). We won gold, and our results outperformed existing benchmarks, so we decided to publish our work. Satya was more unexpected. I participated in a competition with juniors, and while our idea didn’t fully fit the event, we saw potential in it. We submitted it for publication, expecting feedback for improvement, but it got accepted on the first try. Apart from these, I’m working on projects at MIT.",
      },
      {
        question:
          "You have been actively involved in tech-related activities, including Inter IIT Tech Meets and technology societies. How crucial are such activities for students pursuing a tech-focused career?",
        answer:
          " I participated in the Inter IIT Tech Meet twice once in my third year as a member and later in my fourth year as a captain. As a member, my learning curve was steep, I worked on cutting-edge technologies with great seniors and batchmates. It also helped me land an internship. As a captain, the experience was different. I learned leadership, team coordination, and how to manage both technical and non-technical aspects.\n\nSimilarly, being part of tech societies like the Kharagpur Data Analytics Group (KDAG) and Quant Club helped me develop technical and managerial skills. These experiences taught me teamwork, mentorship, and how to work in a corporate setting where hierarchy and collaboration matter.",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What advice would you give to students preparing for placements and internships in data science and machine learning?",
        answer:
          "The most important thing is DSA (Data Structures & Algorithms) even if it’s not directly useful in data science, companies use it as a filtering criterion. Most companies hiring through CDC will test DSA first, so you must prepare well.\n\nFor ML and data roles, the interviews are not very difficult you can prepare in 1–2 months. Go through ML concepts via resources like Intro to ML by Andrew Ng. Also, work on solid projects and internships, as tech PoRs don’t matter much real projects do.",
      },
      {
        question:
          "You have participated in several projects and competitions. What advice would you give to beginners looking to get started in a tech-based career?",
        answer:
          "My journey with competitions started because friends would add me to teams on platforms like Unstop, and I just went along with it. Over time, I realized how beneficial these competitions were.\n\nFor beginners: Find a team having batchmates, juniors, or seniors makes participation easier; Join tech societies they help you find teammates and mentors; Participate in GCs (General Championships), Inter IIT, and Open IIT these give exposure; Look for company-hosted hackathons (e.g., Bajaj, Conserve, MX, Accenture) for more experience.Even if you don’t win, participating puts you on the leaderboard. The more you compete, the better you get.",
      },
      {
        question:
          "How did you manage academics along with multiple research internships, projects, and internships, especially during your last semester?",
        answer:
          "Honestly, I wasn’t able to manage everything perfectly. When you take up too much, you inevitably have to compromise somewhere. I couldn’t give my 100% everywhere, maybe 90% in some areas, 80% in others. My advice would be not to overburden yourself.\n\nThere’s an analogy I found while exploring IIT KGP-related posts before joining: You can divide your time into three major aspects: academics/internships, friends/social life, and sleep. The catch? You can only pick two. If you focus too much on societies and internships, your health might suffer. You don’t always have to stick to just two, but at different times, different priorities will take precedence. Keeping this framework in mind helps in managing priorities effectively. Additionally, time management is crucial, and I credit IIT KGP for teaching me that. Before college, most JEE aspirants don’t have much to manage except studies. But once you enter IIT, distractions and opportunities increase significantly. So, prioritization becomes key.",
      },
      {
        question:
          "How important are soft skills like communication, leadership, and teamwork in a tech-based career?",
        answer:
          "Soft skills are just as important as technical skills, sometimes even more. No matter how good you are at your work, if you can’t communicate with your team or stakeholders, you’ll miss opportunities. The real world isn’t a solo game; even as a solopreneur, you need to interact with clients, agencies, and other professionals. Initially, I was quite introverted and felt anxious about talking to people. Writing LinkedIn posts helped me express myself, and over time, I realized that communicating online and speaking in person aren’t too different.\n\nLeadership is also crucial. As a fresher, you may not need it, but as you gain experience, you’ll have people working under you. A bad leader negatively affects the team, so developing leadership skills is essential not just for others, but for your own sanity too.",
      },
      {
        question:
          "How should students decide whether to stick to their core branch or shift to AI, ML, or data science?",
        answer:
          "If you’re asking someone else what you should do in life, you’re probably approaching it the wrong way. Instead of trying to figure out what you like right away, it’s easier to identify what you don’t like. In your first year, you get exposure to multiple fields like biotech, physics, mathematics, engineering since IIT KGP has interdisciplinary courses. By the second year, you start taking core engineering courses. That’s when you should explore and figure out if your core branch interests you. Second year is relatively less hectic, so it’s a good time to experiment — try data science, web development, finance, consulting, product management, etc. By the end of second year, you’ll have a rough idea of what interests you. But don’t just go by what feels good, evaluate it practically. Consider factors like lifestyle, job locations, financial goals, and long-term aspirations. The key is to make a conscious choice, not one influenced by external pressure.",
      },
      {
        question:
          "How has IIT Kharagpur shaped your journey, and what message would you give to students?",
        answer:
          "IIT KGP has played a huge role in my growth. The people both students and alumni are incredible, and the strong network helps in navigating career paths. Personally, IIT KGP helped me develop leadership and communication skills. If I hadn’t been here, I wouldn’t be as comfortable speaking in this interview. I’ve become more open-minded, adaptable, and confident.\n\nMy advice is Don’t fear making mistakes. College is a unique phase where you have responsibilities but also the freedom to explore. Take risks, learn from experiences, and make the most of your time.",
      },
    ],
  },
};

const details = [
  {
    name: "Ms. Devaki Nandana",
    about:
      "Ms. Devaki (Batch of 2023), is an alumna of the Department of Geology and Geophysics with a minor in economics and micro-specialization in Entrepreneurship and Innovation at IIT Kharagpur. Now an associate at Boston Consulting Group (BCG) and a former Vice President of the Technology Students’ Gymkhana, Devaki shares her insights on her journey to consulting, her experiences in campus leadership, and her advice for students.",
    department: "Department of Geology and Geophysics",
    hall: "Mother Teresa Hall of Residence",
    work: "Associate at Boston Consulting Group (BCG)",
    video: (
      <iframe
        width="560"
        height="315"
        src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/OrwMLGtswBQ?si=2AL2jeY0qpB4ZLPX"
        title="YouTube video player"
        frameborder="0"
        allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share"
        referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin"
        allowfullscreen
      ></iframe>
    ),
    medium:
      "https://medium.com/@sbrciitkgp/spotlight-ms-devaki-nandana-963bdb6f706f",
    linkedin: "https://www.linkedin.com/in/devakinandanakalam/",
    facebook: "https://www.facebook.com/p/devakinandanakalam/",
    instagram: "https://www.instagram.com/nandanakalam/",
    mediumArticle: {
      questions: [
        {
          question:
            "Could you share what inspired you to pursue a career in consulting?",
          answer:
            "During my time at IIT Kharagpur, I was keen to explore various fields that might interest me and broaden my understanding. I dived into machine learning, AI, and project management, which all had their unique appeal. But as I progressed, I realized that my true passion lay in problem solving and making a tangible impact in real world scenarios. Consulting, with its dynamic nature and exposure to diverse industries, seemed like the ideal choice where I could apply my strengths. Additionally, I received great encouragement from my seniors, who saw my potential in consulting. Their guidance was instrumental in helping me envision a consulting career and ultimately join BCG’s Bangalore office. Consulting allows me to address complex challenges and make an impact across sectors, which is incredibly fulfilling.",
        },
        {
          question:
            "How did you adapt your skills from an academic setting to a consulting role?",
          answer:
            "The transition from academics to consulting required significant flexibility and a commitment to continuous learning. My academic background laid the foundation of analytical skills, but I needed to translate that knowledge into practical, real world applications. Experiences in project work during college taught me to adapt my skills, bridging the gap between theoretical knowledge and industry demands. It was challenging to balance everything, but I managed by prioritizing tasks based on deadlines and their importance, ensuring that I stayed on top of my academic performance while also developing professional skills through internships and campus roles. Consulting demands a well rounded profile, where quick thinking and adaptability are essential. Broadening my perspective was key, and BCG’s supportive team environment made the steep learning curve much smoother. It wasn’t easy, but staying disciplined and open to learning made the transition rewarding.",
        },
        {
          question:
            "What have been some of your most memorable experiences working at BCG?",
          answer:
            "My first project at BCG was quite memorable as it involved extensive data analysis and an intense amount of work on Excel. It was challenging at first, but my team’s support and guidance made a huge difference, helping me navigate this learning experience successfully. Another unforgettable project required me to interact with both factory workers and senior executives, providing me with exposure to different perspectives within an organization. A standout moment was presenting to a CEO within just six months of joining BCG — an experience that was both intimidating and deeply rewarding. Currently, I am working with public sector clients in South India, which has been a unique and invaluable experience. Each of these moments has been instrumental in building my confidence, teaching me client interaction skills, and allowing me to see the direct impact of our work.",
        },
        {
          question:
            "What advice would you give to students aspiring to enter the consulting industry?",
          answer:
            "Consulting demands a well rounded skill set, which includes strong academics, relevant internships, and active involvement in extracurriculars. Excelling at multitasking and managing different stakeholders is crucial in this field. For me, the senior junior network at IIT Kharagpur was an invaluable resource, providing me with guidance and insight from people who had been through similar experiences. I strongly encourage students to reach out and engage with seniors, as their perspectives can be incredibly helpful in understanding the skills and mindset needed for consulting. Building relationships with mentors can provide both knowledge and encouragement. Consulting is a competitive field, but with discipline, focus, and the right support network, it’s achievable.",
        },
        {
          question:
            "How did your role as Vice President of the Technology Students’ Gymkhana help you develop as a leader?",
          answer:
            "Serving as Vice President taught me a great deal about responsibility and resilience. Being the first female VP came with its own set of challenges, as I encountered some initial skepticism about my ability to manage the role. However, I focused on proving myself by committing to my responsibilities and demonstrating my dedication to my duties. This role helped me develop confidence in my abilities, and I learned invaluable skills in team management and communication.. Through this role, I also learned to advocate for myself and others, paving the way for future female leaders on campus.",
        },
        {
          question:
            " Could you tell us about your role in campus reopening during the COVID 19 pandemic?",
          answer:
            "During the pandemic, I participated in a case study competition that focused on reopening IIT Kharagpur safely, an experience I found deeply rewarding. We aimed to revive important campus traditions like the Illumination and General Championship, even though we had to work within limited capacity due to health protocols. Seeing these events come to life was incredibly satisfying, as it allowed students to reconnect with campus life in a safe way. The experience underscored the importance of resilience, creativity, and teamwork. It wasn’t just about logistics — it was about bringing back the spirit of our campus, which had been missed by so many. Helping the student community reconnect after such a challenging period was one of my most fulfilling experiences.",
        },
        {
          question:
            "As the first female VP of TSG, did you face any unique challenges, and how did you overcome them?",
          answer:
            "Being the first female VP of the Technology Students’ Gymkhana came with its own set of challenges. There was some initial skepticism and assumptions about my ability to manage the role, which was difficult at first. However, the support from the campus community made a big difference. I focused on proving myself by staying true to my responsibilities and consistently delivering results. Overcoming these challenges helped me build resilience and showed me the importance of confidence and focus. I hope that my experience can serve as an example to others, showing that leadership roles should be open to everyone, regardless of gender. This experience taught me that perseverance and hard work can break down barriers, and I’m grateful for the opportunity to pave the way for future female leaders.",
        },
        {
          question:
            "How did the IIT Kharagpur community contribute to your growth, both personally and professionally?",
          answer:
            "The IIT Kharagpur community played an integral role in my journey, contributing immensely to my personal and professional growth. The support and mentorship from my seniors were crucial. The senior junior culture at IIT Kharagpur fosters a strong sense of collaboration and encourages students to learn from each other’s experiences. This environment helped me build confidence, take on new challenges, and develop essential skills like time management and adaptability. The friendships and networks I built on campus are lifelong, and the skills I honed in this community have been invaluable in consulting, where collaboration and adaptability are paramount.",
        },
        {
          question:
            "What key advice would you like to share with juniors and incoming students?",
          answer:
            "My advice is to make the most of your time in college by exploring various fields and opportunities. Don’t limit yourself — try different things, connect with seniors, and embrace what you’re passionate about. A career in consulting, or any problem solving field, requires you to think creatively and continuously build diverse skills. College is the best time to step out of your comfort zone, as these years are invaluable for growth and self discovery. Take advantage of the resources and opportunities around you; they’ll shape you in ways you might not realize now. Consulting or not, these experiences will help you, no matter where your career takes you.",
        },
      ],
      interviewedBy: (
        <>
          <i>
            <b>Interviewed by — </b>Isha Singhal, Student Member at Students’
            Branding and Relations Cell, IIT Kharagpur.
          </i>
        </>
      ),
    },
  },
  {
    name: "Mr. Prashant Jhangid",
    about:
      "Mr. Prashant Jangid is an alumnus (Batch of 2024) at IIT Kharagpur’s Department of Industrial and Systems Engineering. He is the co-founder and CTO of Heltar, an automation company specializing in customer support, customer engagement, and customer experience management, shares his experiences and advice during a Spotlight Series interview.",
    department: "Department of Industrial and Systems Engineering",
    hall: "Azad Hall of Residence",
    work: "CTO at Heltar",
    video: (
      <iframe
        width="560"
        height="315"
        src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/oD41hPIElUE?si=jVSTRqDPCC7PZB3L"
        title="YouTube video player"
        frameborder="0"
        allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen"
        referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin"
        allowfullscreen
      ></iframe>
    ),
    medium:
      "https://medium.com/@sbrciitkgp/spotlight-mr-prashant-jangid-da505bf40db7",
    linkedin: "https://www.linkedin.com/in/prashantjangid31/",
    facebook: "https://www.facebook.com/prashant.jangid.779642/",
    instagram: null,
    mediumArticle: {
      questions: [
        {
          question:
            "Can you tell us a bit about your experience at IIT Kharagpur over the past five years?",
          answer:
            " It’s been an exciting roller coaster ride! I’ve been involved in everything from academics and career development to extracurricular activities, making friends, and just having fun. IIT Kharagpur has a unique environment — limited resources, many people, and countless opportunities to learn. Adapting to this environment has been a valuable experience, and these five years have taught me a lot. I’ve grown a lot and learned to handle challenges better.",
        },
        {
          question:
            "How did you explore your interests and find your passion during college?",
          answer:
            "My journey began in my first year, around the second semester, during the PDS lab. Initially, I had no background in coding, finance, or emerging technologies. However, the PDS course sparked my interest. Despite a rough start with a D in PDS Theory, I persevered. When COVID hit and the lab went online, I noticed many friends excelling at coding, which motivated me to learn. I dived headfirst into learning coding, data structures, algorithms, different programming languages, and the underlying principles. Thankfully, I was able to turn my initial D in PDS Theory into an A in the lab. This success fueled my interest in competitive programming. During the COVID lockdown, I participated in CodeChef contests and contributed to open-source projects. Starting early gave me a significant advantage.",
        },
        {
          question: "How did internships contribute to your development?",
          answer:
            "By the end of my second year, I landed an internship with a senior student. This internship exposed me to web development and how the theoretical concepts learned in DSA and competitive programming translate to real-world applications. Building a website for the company was an amazing experience — it allowed me to see how algorithms and coding translate into tangible products that people use. This practical experience was both intriguing and motivating.",
        },
        {
          question: "How did freelancing play a role in your journey?",
          answer:
            "I began freelancing at the start of my second year, driven by the desire to make money and gain experience. While the internship provided valuable experience, freelancing offered a corporate-like experience from the comfort of my home. I took on web development projects and helped students with their academic work. It was through freelancing that I identified a demand, and along with my roommate Avyukt Agarwal, who freelanced in business and finance, we decided to join forces and start our own company, Heltar.",
        },
        {
          question:
            "What was the turning point that led to the creation of Heltar?",
          answer:
            "A significant turning point came when Avyukt interned at LimeChat and worked closely with chatbots on WhatsApp. We had previously developed an order management system for our ed-tech business that utilized WhatsApp. This system allowed customers to send assignments or projects directly through WhatsApp. We had a network of 1,500 SMEs and subject matter experts connected on WhatsApp, and we used skill-based filtering to assign projects and bulk messaging for order management.\n\nAvyukt’s experience at LimeChat opened our eyes to the potential of our WhatsApp ecosystem. The emergence of AI and advancements in chatbot technology made us see the possibilities for improving business automation, enhancing customer support, and streamlining operations through AI-powered WhatsApp agents. We recognized the extensive use of WhatsApp in tier 2 and tier 3 cities in India, coupled with the growing preference for automation to save time. AI-powered chatbots could efficiently handle FAQs and customer queries, offering personalized responses in local languages — a crucial feature for reaching users in diverse regions.\n\nOur past business experiences helped us identify a problem and develop a solution. We transitioned from offering customized solutions to building a product that businesses could use to manage their WhatsApp operations. This five-year journey has been about identifying problems, leveraging peer networks, and continuously working towards developing solutions.",
        },
        {
          question:
            "How did you manage extracurricular activities alongside academics and internships?",
          answer:
            "Time management is key. While career growth and academics are important, so is your personal well-being and development. There’s a lot of pressure from various areas like academics, placements, internships, and even curricular internships, which are becoming increasingly common. However, I never limited myself solely to academics.\n\nIn my first year, I participated in extracurricular activities as a crew team member for the Inter IIT sports hosted at Kharagpur. It was an amazing experience to witness the high level of competition in sports alongside academics. My experience playing basketball in school fueled my excitement to participate at the college level. Engaging in such activities helped me stay active and maintain a healthy balance.\n\nI also took on leadership roles, serving as the officiating secretary of sports and games in my second year. We organized virtual marathons and other events to promote fitness during the COVID-19 pandemic. Even now, I continue to play basketball at my hostel. Extracurricular activities offer opportunities for personal growth, leadership development, and networking.",
        },
        {
          question:
            "How important is freelancing for students, and what advice do you have for those considering it?",
          answer:
            "Freelancing is a great way to gain practical experience, earn money, and build a portfolio. It can be a stepping stone to entrepreneurship or a valuable addition to your resume. My advice is to start early, be open to new challenges, and build a strong professional network. It’s important to balance freelancing with academics and other commitments.",
        },
        {
          question:
            "What advice do you have for students starting their entrepreneurial ventures?",
          answer:
            "Identify a problem that people actually care about and build a solution that addresses their needs. Seek feedback from potential customers and iterate on your product based on their input. Building a strong team and seeking mentorship is also crucial. Don’t be afraid to fail; it’s a natural part of the entrepreneurial journey.",
        },
        {
          question:
            "What advice do you have for juniors at IIT Kharagpur regarding their journey and career growth?",
          answer:
            "Be well-rounded. Don’t limit yourself to just academics or internships. Explore different areas of interest, participate in extracurricular activities, and engage in social work. Continuous learning is essential, so keep challenging yourself. Don’t get discouraged by setbacks; focus on building something meaningful and impactful.",
        },
        {
          question: "What are your future plans for Heltar?",
          answer:
            "We aim to expand our customer base and develop new features to enhance our platform’s capabilities. We are also exploring opportunities to integrate AI and machine learning to further improve customer experience and automation. Our goal is to become a leading player in the WhatsApp automation space.",
        },
        {
          question: "Any final thoughts you would like to share?",
          answer:
            "IIT Kharagpur has been an incredible journey for me. The experiences, friendships, and opportunities I’ve gained here have shaped me into the person I am today. I encourage students to make the most of their time at IIT Kharagpur, explore their passions, and never stop learning.",
        },
      ],
      interviewedBy: null,
    },
  },
  {
    name: "Ms. Sruthi Mahalakshmi",
    about:
      "Ms. Sruthi is an alumna of the Department of Agricultural and Food Engineering. She has worked at major companies like KPMG, Deloitte and Bain & Company where she also received True North Scholarship. She has also represented IIT Kharagpur at Inter IIT Social and Cultural Meet. ",
    department: "Department of Agricultural and Food Engineering",
    hall: "Mother Teresa Hall of Residence",
    work: "Associate Consultant, Bain & Company",
    video: (
      <iframe
        width="560"
        height="315"
        src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/UkPls558yfY?si=agzVlN0Pq6Xwime8"
        title="YouTube video player"
        frameborder="0"
        allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen"
        referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin"
        allowfullscreen
      ></iframe>
    ),
    medium:
      "https://medium.com/@sbrciitkgp/spotlight-ms-sruthi-mahalakshmi-73b94f017dda",
    linkedin: "https://www.linkedin.com/in/sruthi-mahalakshmi-r-l-0aa6611b2/",
    facebook: "https://www.facebook.com/sruthi.mahalakshmi.5",
    instagram: "https://www.instagram.com/sruthimahalakshmi_/",
    mediumArticle: {
      questions: [
        {
          question:
            "How would you describe your overall experience at IIT Kharagpur?",
          answer:
            "My experience at IIT Kharagpur has been both ‘exciting’ and ‘enriching.’ It’s thrilling because every morning ushers in new possibilities. I’ve created numerous memorable moments, and the exposure to a wide range of uncommon events has been truly enlightening. In retrospect, I can confidently say that my journey here has been both thrilling and enlightening. I take pride in where I stand today and feel a sense of accomplishment.",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Many students who come to IIT often become deeply engrossed in their studies, losing touch with extracurricular activities. How did IIT KGP support you in pursuing your interests in Yoga, debating, and other extracurriculars?",
          answer:
            "While preparing for the JEE, extracurricular activities often take a backseat as students focus solely on academics. However, once you clear the JEE and enrol at IIT, you find the time and opportunities to engage in a diverse array of pursuits. Breaking the monotony with extracurricular activities becomes imperative. IIT Kharagpur offers a multitude of societies, clubs, and research groups. Furthermore, you can participate in projects aligned with your research interests and take part in Inter IIT competitions across sports, sociocultural, and technological domains. The ample opportunities enable you to explore and discover your passions. Engaging in these activities allows you to strike a balance between your academic commitments and extracurricular interests, which is crucial for holistic personality development.",
        },
        {
          question:
            "You represented IIT Kharagpur at the Inter IIT social and cultural meet. Could you share your experience and how you managed the pressure in those situations?",
          answer:
            "The Inter IIT Social and Cultural Meet was an exceptionally special experience for me. It not only inspired us to perform at our best but also taught us the value of teamwork in securing victory for IIT Kharagpur. The motivation to excel is driven by the desire to make our institute proud. I was fortunate to be part of the Gold-winning debate team. When you are passionate about something, you invest your wholehearted effort, and the results tend to be in your favour. The pressure dissipates when you are deeply committed and driven.",
        },
        {
          question:
            "As the Institute’s women representative, how does IIT KGP address the issues faced by female students?",
          answer:
            "IIT KGP is highly receptive to student concerns. The women’s department representatives collectively form the Female Student Council, providing a direct avenue for female students to voice their concerns, whether they are personal, academic, or related to any other aspect. Afterward, we collaborate to ensure the best possible resolution. Another option is to file a complaint with the Internal Complaints Committee, the institute’s official Sexual Harassment Redressal Forum. Additionally, there is a Student Grievance Redressal Committee where female students can reach out to any faculty member or the Dean for assistance. Prof. Koel Chaudhury, an associate Dean, oversees the welfare of all female students on campus. These are some of the available avenues, and in addition, each year’s student representatives can also be approached.",
        },
        {
          question:
            "You have not only participated but excelled in competitive yoga and debating. How did you identify your talents, which many people find challenging?",
          answer:
            "Identifying one’s talents often involves gauging personal enjoyment and deriving fulfilment from a particular activity. It also entails assessing whether the effort invested yields outcomes that align with expectations. When these criteria are met, one is naturally motivated to persist and excel. It’s essential to ask oneself such introspective questions to guide the discovery of one’s talents. Hard work combined with passion usually leads to favourable results.",
        },
        {
          question:
            "You secured internships at major companies like KPMG and Deloitte. How challenging was the process, and how did you prepare for it?",
          answer:
            "Securing the internship at KPMG came as an unexpected opportunity, thanks to a friend working there who informed me about a team in need of additional members. I submitted my resume, which seemed a perfect fit, and subsequently, after an interview, I was selected. Many individuals tend to hesitate when it comes to exploring new opportunities and uncharted territories. However, I viewed my KPMG internship as a serendipitous blessing that significantly influenced my career path. I thrived in the dynamic team environment and fast-paced work setting. Subsequently, I explored internships in the specific domain of consulting. The opportunity at Deloitte presented itself through referrals on LinkedIn from Deloitte employees. Fortunately, I progressed through two rounds of interviews, the first assessing problem-solving abilities and business acumen, and the second focusing on case analysis to evaluate my suitability for the mobility sector. This is how I secured my internship at Deloitte.",
        },
        {
          question:
            "You also interned at Bain and received their True North scholarship. Can you provide more details about that experience?",
          answer:
            "My internships at KPMG and Deloitte exposed me to the consulting field, which ultimately influenced my decision to pursue a career in consulting. In 2022, I participated in the inaugural launch of the Bain True North scholarship program in India. This program specifically targets women in their pre-final year of studies. The application process involves three stages. In the first stage, applicants are required to submit their resume and an essay on a given topic. The second stage comprises an aptitude and personality test, followed by a series of interviews in the final stage. The first interview focused on estimation and case interpretation, while the second was more of a fit round involving interaction with management. Upon successfully completing all rounds, I was awarded both the scholarship and an internship opportunity. My experience at Bain was highly rewarding, as I worked alongside like-minded individuals in a high-pressure, fast-paced environment, gaining valuable hands-on experience working with clients.",
        },
        {
          question:
            "How did you decide to pursue a career in consulting? Did you consider this path from your first year, and does your department influence your choice in consulting?",
          answer:
            "I didn’t initially plan for a career in consulting during my first year. I was open to various opportunities and hadn’t yet explored the consulting field. However, I had a clear inclination toward roles that emphasise teamwork, creativity, leadership qualities, and effective communication. Consulting emerged as a natural fit for these strengths. Even then, I remained open to diverse experiences. My first internship was as a product manager at a startup named Beepkart. Subsequently, opportunities arose for internships at KPMG and Deloitte, where I gained exposure to consulting. It was during my Deloitte internship that I realised my true calling. Supportive mentors played a pivotal role in helping me navigate the consulting industry, understand project dynamics, and adapt to the corporate environment. Their guidance and encouragement solidified my decision to pursue consulting as a career path. It’s worth noting that the choice of one’s department doesn’t significantly influence a career in consulting; personal exploration and growth ultimately determine one’s career trajectory.",
        },
        {
          question:
            "What are your future plans? If not consulting, what alternative career path would you have pursued?",
          answer:
            "The future is inherently uncertain, and I am adaptable, ready to embrace opportunities as they come. If not consulting, then I would have certainly ventured into startups, specifically related to hydroponics and vertical farming. I’ve been interested in it for a long time and I do think there is a strong future for it.",
        },
        {
          question: "What advice would you like to give to your juniors?",
          answer:
            "One advice that I would definitely like to give to the juniors, is to not let go of opportunities. IIT Kharagpur presents to you a lot of opportunities to showcase your talent and interests and shying awaying from those opportunities would be the biggest mistake one would be making. Each opportunity is different and each opportunity is a pathway for another opportunity. So, never let go of your opportunities and even if you think you are not ready, just go ahead and grab it.",
        },
      ],
      interviewedBy: (
        <i>
          <b>Interviewed by — </b>Shubham Pingale, Student Member at Branding
          and Relations Cell, IIT Kharagpur.
        </i>
      ),
    },
  },
  {
    name: "Mr. Bharat Uday",
    about:
      "Mr. Bharat is an alumnus of the Department of Electrical Engineering. He worked as a Research intern at Deakins University at Australia, on open CV and image processing. He won the International Golf Junior Training Program- Singapore organised by TaylorMade.",
    department: "Department of Electrical Engineering",
    hall: "Meghnad Saha Hall of Residence",
    work: "Associate Consultant, Bain & Company",
    video: (
      <iframe
        width="560"
        height="315"
        src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/A3Pmm58TtKc?si=dgpORZFINb5L1wko"
        title="YouTube video player"
        frameborder="0"
        allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen"
        referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin"
        allowfullscreen
      ></iframe>
    ),
    medium:
      "https://medium.com/@sbrciitkgp/spotlight-mr-bharat-uday-ccffbd276971",
    linkedin: "https://www.linkedin.com/in/bharat-uday/",
    facebook: "https://www.facebook.com/profile.php?id=100060773738831",
    instagram: null,
    mediumArticle: {
      questions: [
        {
          question:
            "What is your point of view regarding Kharagpur’s culture in shaping one’s future? How did your experience at Kharagpur contribute to your current achievements and identity?",
          answer:
            "IIT Kharagpur indeed possesses a very diverse culture. There are many events happening on campus all the time. However, the most significant aspect for me is the interaction between juniors and seniors. Despite being part of various societies and clubs, you can approach any senior or even an alum for help at any stage. Secondly, you get to explore many new things, and sometimes you might find your niche in unexpected areas.",
        },
        {
          question:
            "What were your involvements in IIT Kharagpur, and what did you learn from them?",
          answer:
            "I was heavily involved on campus for two years, given that they were online. To elaborate, I was part of seven societies. However, I wouldn’t recommend this, as it may suggest a lack of dedication. Currently, I am only in the Business Club, which was my intended focus from the beginning.",
        },
        {
          question:
            "You achieved a department change after the first year. What valuable insights do you have for freshmen aspiring for the same?",
          answer:
            "Many individuals come here with the goal of a department change, much like I did. Department change was my primary objective in my first year, motivating me to study extensively. So, if you aim for a department change, study diligently in your first year, setting aside other distractions, as this will ensure your path going forward.",
        },
        {
          question:
            "You worked at Deakins University, Australia as a Research intern, which ranks among top 1% of all universities. Could you tell us how you secured this amazing opportunity and share your experience at Deakins?",
          answer:
            "There is an International Relations Cell portal that offers foreign training activities. You can apply with your CV and cover letter from your second year onwards. I applied and got shortlisted at Deakins University primarily because of my work involving open CV and image processing. The subsequent steps involved an interview, after which they extended an offer to me.",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Could you please tell us about your other research internships and how you obtained them?",
          answer:
            "I worked with professors from IIMs, but I wouldn’t classify these experiences as internships as they lasted only about a month. They were primarily for gaining experience, especially in finance and quantitative strategies. I obtained most of my other internships through LinkedIn networking or reaching out through cold emails. Many of these internships were in the strategy domain, which I explored in my second year. During my time, securing internships was relatively easy because of the online structure, but for you, completing one or two impactful internships where you gain valuable experience should suffice.",
        },
        {
          question:
            "We are aware of your achievements in sports. Could you please share your sporting accomplishments and how you managed them alongside your academics?",
          answer:
            "While my focus primarily remains on academics, I do engage in golf, a sport I’ve been playing since the seventh grade. Golf isn’t something I can pursue on campus. However, during my second-year vacation, I participated in an international tournament held in Singapore.",
        },
        {
          question:
            "You also secured a CDC internship as a Summer Associate at Bain & Co. What did you do to prepare for this, and what advice would you give other juniors seeking internships in the consulting domain? Also, why did you choose this profile over others?",
          answer:
            "I would advise against exclusively choosing consulting as your profile, as the selection process can be quite unpredictable, with few openings. Consulting interviews often involve guesstimates and case studies. For case preparation, there are available books, and you can also form study groups with peers interested in consulting. As for my choice, the chance to work at Bain & Co. during my summers was incredibly rewarding due to the stimulating problem-solving environment and the people I had the opportunity to collaborate with.",
        },
        {
          question:
            "As your CDC placement is forthcoming, what are your future aspirations and plans, considering your diverse range of achievements and experiences? Which profiles are you currently prioritizing for CDC placement?",
          answer:
            "Looking ahead, my aspirations revolve around either a role in finance or consulting. The appeal of consulting is strong due to the enriching experiences I had during my internship at Bain & Co. Post-college, I’m also considering pursuing a Master’s degree.",
        },
        {
          question: "What advice would you offer to your fellow juniors?",
          answer:
            "1st years: Discover what you want to do, try new things, talk to a lot of seniors, don’t hesitate to initiate conversations.\n\n2nd year:Identify 1–2 specific areas where your skills might excel, then concentrate on developing expertise in those niches. Invest time in researching extensively, and actively pursuing internship opportunities in those domains.\n\n3rd year: Start building up on your domains and seek options for what you will do after Kharagpur.\n\n4th year: Support your younger peers.\n\nAnd regardless of the years make sure to have fun because you can’t relive those moments.",
        },
      ],
      interviewedBy: null,
    },
  },
  {
    name: "Mr. Yogesh Chawla",
    about:
      "Mr. Yogesh is an alumnus of the Department of Agricultural and Food Engineering. He was awarded the Honda Y-E-S Award 2022, Yogesh also worked as a research intern at Purdue University and Iowa State University, and his work was selected for the American Society of Agricultural and Biological Engineers Annual International Meet 2022.",
    department: "Department of Agricultural and Food Engineering",
    hall: "Meghnad Saha Hall of Residence",
    work: "Graduate Research Assistant, University of Nebraska-Lincoln",
    video: (
      <iframe
        width="560"
        height="315"
        src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WicwoC3c2HA?si=cPz9egTsaPZJU5U3"
        title="YouTube video player"
        frameborder="0"
        allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen"
        referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin"
        allowfullscreen
      ></iframe>
    ),
    medium:
      "https://medium.com/@sbrciitkgp/spotlight-mr-yogesh-chawla-dace8b195ceb",
    linkedin: "https://www.linkedin.com/in/yogesh-chawla/",
    facebook: "https://www.facebook.com/yogeshchawla2850",
    instagram: null,
    mediumArticle: {
      questions: [
        {
          question:
            "How may one improve their life after joining IIT Kharagpur, in your opinion? What changes have you made in yourself since joining IIT Kharagpur?",
          answer:
            "The most important thing after joining IIT Kharagpur is that you should explore everything possible here. I spent my first year talking with most of my seniors and even alumni. Being a part of the GYWS Sponsorship team, I had the chance to talk to alumni. So apart from seniors of hall and department, I spoke to many alumni who gave me a huge perspective about what you can achieve through this college. I believe that the best thing is to explore everything, talk to as many people as possible, and then eventually, you will get an idea about what you want to do.",
        },
        {
          question:
            "You were awarded the Honda Young Engineer and Scientists (Y-E-S) Award organized by Honda Foundation, Japan. Please briefly explain the award you received and the process through which you were selected.",
          answer:
            " The Honda Y-E-S Award is one of the most prestigious awards. Its process was both amazing as well as grilling. So, it was a 3-step process: the first consisted of a subjective interview where general questions were given, and we had to answer them in the format of 1000 words per question. After selecting around 300 students, round 2 involved Honda employees who grilled these students based on their CVs, and finally, 30 students were selected. The Director of Tata Energy Research Institute (TERI) took the final interview.",
        },
        {
          question:
            "You have a keen interest in research, particularly the application of ML and DL to agriculture. What tips will you give to the students who also want to go into the research field?",
          answer:
            "Research is a very long-time goal, so first you should start taking on some basic projects at your own university and then definitely you should apply to foreign universities to get a flavour of how professors in other countries work because every country has a different work culture. Moreover, research is all about your interest because you will build something new. You can approach as many professors as you want and do as many projects as possible to gain more knowledge and get hands-on experience. That will really help you.",
        },
        {
          question:
            "You also got a research internship at Iowa State University. Can you describe your internship experience and how you got this opportunity? What tips will you give to people also looking for such an internship?",
          answer:
            "I got this opportunity through the cold mailing process. The process includes mailing professors by yourself; the complete cover letter is very specific to each professor. This cover letter comprises your introduction, your previous work, your interested research area, the concerned professor’s research papers, etc. However, the accuracy is very low because you will have to mail hundreds of professors in order to get around 10 positive responses.",
        },
        {
          question:
            "You have also worked as a research intern at Purdue University, and your work was selected for the American Society of Agricultural and Biological Engineers Annual International Meet 2022. Can you brief us on this work?",
          answer:
            "Yes, this was my 1st research internship after my second year, and I got this again through the cold mailing process. We worked remotely for more than 6 months and came up with a very good paper which we then submitted to the mentioned conference.",
        },
        {
          question:
            "At the 10th Inter IIT Tech Meet, you also won a solo gold in Silicon Labs’ High-Prep Social Entrepreneurship Challenge. Could you share your experience with this accomplishment?",
          answer:
            "We can all agree that Inter-IIT Tech Meet is one of the most amazing experiences for anyone at IIT KGP because our institute has a name for being very hard in Inter-IIT since you form a team of the smartest people present in the specific field. The bonding that you create in the team is also amazing. The day and night working during the 2 months is a different experience as you literally create something from scratch. So even the satisfaction that you get is really unmatched. We created an IOT-based truck monitoring system for this event and presented it. The best thing is that we not only got gold but a solo gold in this event. So, the experience was amazing.",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Along with all these achievements, you have also done excellent in academics. Can you brief us on how you are able to manage academics along with all these research activities?",
          answer:
            "Specifically for academics, take courses that you like and want to explore, especially from 3rd year onwards. Also, attend as many classes as possible since you get the maximum idea in the class only. What everyone usually does is that 2 weeks before the exam, just leave everything and start focusing on your exam. I think that in those 2 weeks if you study day and night, you can easily do well in academics.",
        },
        {
          question:
            "You have also won the Vinod Gupta Leadership Scholarship Award. Can you brief us about this award and how you got this award?",
          answer:
            "This award is specifically for the 3rd year students of the Department of Agriculture and Food Engineering since Mr. Vinod Gupta is from our department. So, I applied for this award, and the major thing that they looked for in this award is your contributions to KGP, specifically to your department and hall. And at this time, I had the Honda award as well as 2 Inter-IIT golds. Also, I had a few involvements in the hall and was the Department Representative last year. So, this is what I showed when applying for this award.",
        },
        {
          question:
            "What are your future plans after graduating from IIT KGP? Are you looking to go into the research domain?",
          answer:
            "For sure. I am planning to do a Ph.D. in Agritech, and this summer, I am going to the University of Calgary for my MITACS internship. I also got an opportunity at Cornell University, and most probably, I’m planning to apply there only.",
        },
        {
          question: "According to you, what is the best thing about IIT KGP?",
          answer:
            "My journey started when I was randomly scrolling through LinkedIn. I found a senior, Ms. Swastika Dutta, who had mentioned that she would be joining Stanford for a Master’s in Computer Science. Being new, I didn’t really know that people from KGP also went to universities like Stanford. After contacting her, I got to know that she had even done foreign projects during her time. I told her that even I am interested in research and asked if she could help me. She’s actually my mentor because she taught me everything, like writing emails, how to find professors, how to do research, etc. In my 2nd year, I mailed nearly 200 professors to find one research intern and ended up doing 2 over that summer. I have never met her yet, and it was entirely through WhatsApp. I find this to be the best part of KGP. Here, you will find people who might not know you but still go out of the way just to help you. They will help you to be anything you want.",
        },
        {
          question: "What are your suggestions to your juniors at IIT KGP?",
          answer:
            "I suggest interacting with as many people as possible and getting a complete idea about what others in this college are doing. Don’t get restricted to any particular idea or follow others blindly. Just follow your heart, do whatever you like, and explore everything because once you do that, you will at least get to know what you do not have to do. Take advice from various seniors as you never know who you will talk to and who will give you some fundae that will change your life.",
        },
      ],
      interviewedBy: (
        <i>
          <b>Interviewed by- </b>Aadit Shah, Student Member, Branding and
          Relations Cell, IIT Kharagpur.
        </i>
      ),
    },
  },
  {
    name: "Mr. Aryansh Singh",
    about:
      "Branding and Relations Cell, IIT Kharagpur hereby brings the 2nd entry of a brand new edition of the Spotlight, Mr. Aryansh Singh, a 4th-year undergraduate student of the Department of Humanities and Social Sciences. ",
    department: "Department of Humanities and Social Sciences",
    hall: "Patel Hall of Residence",
    work: "Associate, Boston Consulting Group (BCG)",
    video: (
      <iframe
        width="560"
        height="315"
        src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/pBrJq3OUmjc?si=__9OsclHy4scLqhd"
        title="YouTube video player"
        frameborder="0"
        allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen"
        referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin"
        allowfullscreen
      ></iframe>
    ),
    medium:
      "https://medium.com/@sbrciitkgp/spotlight-mr-aryansh-singh-da92ed73ffaf",
    linkedin: "https://www.linkedin.com/in/aryansh/",
    facebook: "https://www.facebook.com/aryanshs75",
    instagram: "https://www.instagram.com/aryanshsinghh/",
    mediumArticle: {
      questions: [
        {
          question:
            "According to you, how can a person improve himself or herself after joining IIT Kharagpur, and what improvements have you made in your life after joining this IIT?",
          answer:
            " IIT Kharagpur is a journey in itself. I was always born and brought up in Delhi NCR. So once I came to Kharagpur, it was a great transition for me. I got to interact with the people from diverse backgrounds raising from different backgrounds, societies, and thought processes. And in the end, it shaped my perspective a lot. Now I can accustom myself better in highly alien environments. I can interact with different kinds of people, which was a great learning experience for me.",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The whole KGP Junta knows about Kgp Launchpad. It is a single source for all the academic and non-academic stuff. What inspired you to create KGP Launchpad, and how did you create it?",
          answer:
            "When I was in my second year, a lot of the first years who came into the college felt like everybody was living in the online mode; everybody was affected by the coronavirus pandemic. So one thing I witnessed was that when we were in our first year, we had a lot of interaction with our seniors. We used to go to their rooms, or they used to come to our wings and tell us that this is how stuff works. These are the societies you can join and the posters you can see on the walls. But that aspect was missing to a very large extent in the pandemic. So once we realized that this was a problem that every fresher of IIT Kharagpur was facing, I decided to brainstorm on it in my second year. Eventually, in my 3rd year, I proceeded to launch the application. So I had a good team of people around me who were also motivated to work on the cause, and eventually, we released the application, and now it has more than 3000 downloads.",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Can you briefly explain your work at Parliamentary Constituency Task Force and the transformation program for Chief Minister’s Office?",
          answer:
            "Yeah, so this was a very interesting decision. We do a lot of orthodox internships. So I also started with finance, statistics, and public policy internships, but afterward, I realized that I wanted to do something challenging that maybe I wouldn’t be able to do after college and would have some sort of new understanding of some unexplored terrains for me. So I learned about feeding India. I reached out to the head of Feeding India, Mr. Vishal Kumar. I learned a lot under his guidance. In the summer of 2022, I served as the first summer intern, so I ultimately gained much knowledge from him. I worked with the team, got to know the nuances of the entire ecosystem, and eventually, I worked with the Office of the Honorable Chief Minister of Meghalaya, the Office of the Honorable Cabinet Minister Shri Anurag Thakur. And at the end of the day, I was there in a meeting where we had to co-create policies for around 7,00,000. People. So, it was a fantastic experience for any 21-year-old, and I am grateful for it.",
        },
        {
          question:
            "You also worked as a research associate at Harvard Business School, which is a dream for many people, including me. What did you learn throughout your internship, and how did you succeed in getting this intern?",
          answer:
            "It’s again a fascinating story that one of my friends was applying for an internship, and I was also applying. I was looking into Universities like the University of British Columbia, a somewhat lower-ranked university, about how I can get a research intern there. So my friend just came to me and said, “If you are going for a research internship, why not aim for the moon?”\nSo he said to start with MIT, Stanford, or Harvard, and I started doing it. I just sent a couple of emails to professors at Harvard, and one professor found my research statement overlapping with what she was doing. And then, I got into the project, which was a great experience. I learned about their research culture and how they think about approaching different problem statements, and overall it was a great experience.",
        },
        {
          question:
            "You also got a CDC internship as a summer associate at Boston Consulting Group. What have you done to prepare for this, and what advice would you give other juniors seeking an internship in the consulting domain?",
          answer:
            " Yeah, so this decision was an accumulation of everything I had done over the past 3 years. So I realized that I had shifted from finance to statistics to public policy to innovation sciences to strategy. Then I realized my core interest lies in solving problems rather than working in a particular domain. After talking to a lot of seniors who are in the consulting sphere, consulting was a natural choice for me to pursue. After that, I got shortlisted by all these consulting firms, BCG, Bain, and LEK Consulting, that came on campus. I decided that BCG would be the best place for me to work in the long run based on my case, the advice of my seniors, and the interview rounds that ultimately took place.",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Currently, you are working as a Student Venture Partner at Picus Capital. What is your aim behind joining this, and what tips will you give the students interested in entrepreneurship?",
          answer:
            "So this is a very exclusive program that I found out about last year. So ever since I got to know them, I saw a guy from IIT Bombay being the student venture partner. So then I dwelled further deep into this and got to know that only 5 institutes in India- IIT Delhi, Bombay, and apart from that IIM Ahmedabad, Bangalore, and Calcutta had this program running. So I just approached the team at Picus Capital. I will let them know that, see the founders of HCL, Swiggy, and Innovaccer; all these people are legendary people, and these are from IIT Kharagpur. So why not install a branch at IIT Kharagpur as well, where I can connect with my alumni, talk to aspiring startup founders, and learn more about the ecosystem? So the team also felt through. I had a couple of rounds of interviews and eventually became the Student Venture Partner. So far, it has been amazing. I had the chance to explore several different industries and speak with founders from all backgrounds; one day, I spoke with 1992 IIT Kanpur alumni, and the next day, with 2018 NMIMS graduates. So it’s a very diverse experience, and I absolutely loved doing it.",
        },
        {
          question:
            "How are you able to manage your academics while working on these internships and projects?",
          answer:
            "So, I found a group of like-minded people who were interested in stuff beyond academics; apart from focusing on their academics, they were also exploring competitions and different internships and projects. So we just made it a routine that we will let our mentors know that this is our examination timeline rather than hiding it from our mentors that, No, we don’t have any exams. I said, “Yes! we do have our exams at this point, and during the course of these 2 weeks, we wouldn’t be able to give as much time.” So we used to study day in and day out at that point, which eventually led to a decent CG, which helped me back in an internship. And obviously, that is something I would focus on for everybody, especially all my juniors at IIT Kharagpur, that your CV will be very important. So while doing these side projects and getting into different programs, you should also focus on your academics.",
        },
        {
          question:
            "You have attended various competitions, including American Express Campus Super Bowl, EY Case Study, and the Hero Case Challenge. Can you describe your overall experience in all these challenges?",
          answer:
            "So when I was in my first year, I used to see stories of my seniors going to London or going to some random competitions, winning prizes, and the photographs with the big checks, and that was too inspiring to me. So I just started participating in competitions right from my first year. I did a case study at Spring Fest that was initially my first case study, and I went on developing the same. And even right now, I keep doing competitions. I find out some opportunities on LinkedIn, some of them on Unstop, and at the end of the day, now that even though I have the expertise of the last 4 years, I have started winning some of these competitions, got a phone, cash prizes, and some intangible memories out of these competitions. As a result, it’s been a wonderful experience, and I would like to encourage all of my friends and juniors who want to compete to do so. I will be pleased to support them.",
        },
        {
          question: "What are your suggestions to your juniors at IIT KGP?",
          answer:
            "So my suggestion to my juniors is to find people who invest in your growth story. This is a very deep concept that I realized through the course of interacting with more than one thousand people at IIT Kharagpur. So there were seniors who used to look out after me, have I got an internship or not? What am I doing in this particular summer? Is my CG suffering or not? Am I able to cope with the pressure of my society, my other commitments, the cell, or anything else? So those people shaped too much of my KGP journey because they had been through the places that I was in. Because one thing that happens with batchmates is that we are in the same boat. It is possible that we are unaware of the difficulties that we may face in the long run. But I had great seniors who used to guide me and who were invested in my growth story. The day I got an internship, they also felt fulfilled, that yes, the amount of effort and hard work they put into grooming me and mentoring me also helped them feel happy in the longer term. So my advice to all of my juniors would be to find people who invest in your growth story. There will always be meaningful people who would be more than happy to help you in the long run, which just changes everything.",
        },
      ],
      interviewedBy: (
        <i>
          <b>Interviewed by - </b>Aditya Sharma, Student Member, Branding and
          Relations Cell, IIT Kharagpur
        </i>
      ),
    },
  },
  {
    name: "Ms. Vaidehi Gupta",
    about:
      "Branding and Relations Cell, IIT Kharagpur hereby brings a brand new edition of spotlight with a new entry, Ms. Vaidehi Gupta, an alumna of the Department of Physics.",
    department: "Department of Physics",
    hall: "Sarojini Naidu/Indira Gandhi Hall of Residence",
    work: "Research Assistant, University of Minnesota",
    video: (
      <iframe
        width="560"
        height="315"
        src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/auJ1Q8Uv3wM?si=0n3oJG9a-yILXL8Z"
        title="YouTube video player"
        frameborder="0"
        allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen"
        referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin"
        allowfullscreen
      ></iframe>
    ),
    medium:
      "https://medium.com/@sbrciitkgp/spotlight-ms-vaidehi-gupta-ab216facb23f",
    linkedin: "https://www.linkedin.com/in/vaidehi--gupta/",
    facebook: "https://www.facebook.com/vaidehi.gupta.5872682",
    instagram: null,
    mediumArticle: {
      questions: [
        {
          question: "How has your life changed after joining IIT Kharagpur?",
          answer:
            "Since I was from a rural background, we did not have any extraordinary facilities for proper education. That is why I had to move out of my house to Kota to get a proper education and guidance for the JEE Examination. Also, I was the first girl child in my home, and there was a lot of gender inequality pressure on me to do something notable, the reason again being I was a girl. So life has definitely been better than what it used to be a few years ago. Things have eased out since then.",
        },
        {
          question:
            "How did you build your interest in research and specifically Astrophysics?",
          answer:
            "I first developed my interest in sky-watching when I was eight years old. During childhood, everyone becomes amused by the stars and the night sky. But for me, I was deeply enthralled by their physics. There were a huge number of doubts in my mind regarding space and its bodies, and probably these doubts have led me to pursue research in Astrophysics.",
        },
        {
          question:
            "How were you able to manage your academics along with the various projects you’ve been working on?",
          answer:
            "Managing multiple things is not a big deal or a daunting task. You just have to manage your time efficiently by sacrificing some of your daily leisure activities and utilizing that time to do any other productive work. It might be anything such as sports, singing, dancing, sketching, or coding; in my case, it was the project work. I used to attend all the classes and revise the syllabus daily on the weekdays, and I used to do my research work on Saturdays and Sundays.",
        },
        {
          question: "What are your other involvements in KGP?",
          answer:
            " I love poetry, so I am an editor at the TLS (Technology Literary Society). I write poems and perform the same sometimes.",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Can you please brief us about your research work at the University of Minnesota?",
          answer:
            "I worked at the University of Minnesota under Dr Michael Coughlin on the paper “Foraging with MUSHROOMS: A Mixed-Integer Linear Programming Scheduler for Multimessenger Target of Opportunity Searches with the Zwicky Transient Facility” where we created a better scheduler than the one currently used by LIGO to detect gravitational waves.",
        },
        {
          question:
            "What is the procedure for getting a foreign internship or a project under a professor of an abroad university? What are the perks of the same?",
          answer:
            "There are a lot of ways through which you can get a Foreign Internship/Project. The best way in KGP is to get in touch with seniors who have already done the same. They are the best people to guide you through this. The other thing is you can search for various Internship Programs on the internet. MITACS Globalink Research Internship and DAAD are some of the many funded Projects. Usually, all foreign projects and internships are funded by the respective organization, but ultimately it differs with programs. It’s actually quite risky to rely on just a single internship/project because, ultimately thousands of students would be applying for a very small number of seats. Cold mailing is also an option where you mail various professors matching your interests and hope that you get ample responses from their side. A proper Cover Letter, Resume, and Transcript are the basic documents required for applying for a Foreign Internship/Project.",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Can you please shed light on the very common debate of “Core vs. Non-Core”?",
          answer:
            "I believe that pursuing what you like will yield the best results be it core or non-core. Ultimately the field you choose matters a lot. You would have to work your entire life on the specific domain. So it is highly recommended to follow your interests. The harsh reality is that Non-Core jobs pay you a lot when compared to Core jobs, but it is a balance between your interests and the financial requirement that you must take care of.",
        },
        {
          question:
            "What are your future plans once you graduate from IIT KGP?",
          answer:
            "Right now I am thinking of doing PhD in the field of Astrophysics. There is a slight chance of me pursuing a combined Masters with PhD in the same field.",
        },
        {
          question: "Have you decided on where to begin your further studies?",
          answer:
            "I have not yet thought about this because further studies is one such thing where you cannot decide the place to pursue your PhD/Masters on your own. There are lot of factors which matter for that reason.",
        },
        {
          question:
            "What is your advice for the freshers who would be starting their journey at Kgp?",
          answer:
            "The main thing you listen here is the concept of “CG doesn’t matter”, but let me clear you the fact that your CGPA does matter for the internships and placements. It hurts to see my first year CGPA even now. There would be a huge number of challenges through your journey in KGP, but facing and overcoming them is what that makes you an IITian.",
        },
      ],
      interviewedBy: (
        <i>
          <b>Interviewed by: </b>Ishan Jindal
        </i>
      ),
    },
  },
];

export { details, latest };
